<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Pilgrim for A.I.</title>
    <link>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Pilgrim for A.I.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Roles in Growing AI</title>
      <link>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-human-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-human-roles/</guid>
      <description>I would rather see intelligence as an ability to grow in knowledge and wisdom than as a product made by genius engineers that is ready for sale. If we really wish AI to own the same intellectual ability as us, we should be aware of the process of how we develop our intelligence. We, as intelligent beings, are born as a blank sheet of paper. To acquire intellectual growing, children need to learn from the environment, parents, teachers, friends and even opponents except engineers, that is, children need to learn from interaction with other humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task System for machines V.S. Education System for Humans</title>
      <link>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-task-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-task-systems/</guid>
      <description>Current machine learning and deep learning models are trained by tasks that come mostly from real-life applications with practical purposes. Few tasks are designed specially and systematically for the purpose of studying pure intelligence. Why is this very important? Much efforts today in the AI community have been put on designing AI models that are AI&amp;rsquo;s brains, whereas less studies are concentrated on how to design and organize a series of tasks that can help AI grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objective Functions V.S. Life Purposes</title>
      <link>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-objectives/</guid>
      <description>Each time I attempt to see intelligence in machine learning models, there would be a doubt rising in my head - how could intelligence, characterized by high-level abstraction capability, be acquired simply by a gradient descent process reaching convergence? I would rather believe that the journey of pursuing intelligence is a back-and-forth, twist-and-turns, and chaotic-and-conscious process with loops, eventually jumping out of loops and reaching some enlightment point. Therefore, it cannot be achieved only with one single objective formulated by one specific optimizatoin problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Neural Nets V.S. Human Brain Nets</title>
      <link>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.xiaoranxu.com/thinking/about-architectures/</guid>
      <description>There are two major theories of the brain&amp;rsquo;s cognitive function - the theory of modularity and the theory of distributive processing. Instead of asking whether brain&amp;rsquo;s regions are functionally interconnected or specialized, I tend to think of them as complementary to each other.
For the modularity theory, specialized regions are domain specific for different cognitive processes. From the evolutionary perspective, human mind evolved with enhanced functionality developing as a result of its increasing fitting capability to gain more adaptiveness, such as prefrontal cortex that handles high-level cognitive processes, and visual area V4 and V5 in charge of the perception of color and vision motion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>